Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, June 12, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Short, C. W.
    Lexington, Ky., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Cross, recently appointed to chair in the medical school at Lexington. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 22, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Librarian of A.P.S., London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Daubeny, professor of chemistry at Oxford. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 18, 1837; 8 1/2" x 10 5/8"; Beasley, R. W.
    Havre, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Henry Delaroche. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 30, 1837; 7 3/8" x 9 5/8"; Walsh, Robert
    Paris, 2 pp. and address. L.S. Safe arrival of his daughters in Paris. His own poor health. Well-wishes for Institution for the Blind. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 5, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p. address A.L.S. Introducing J. S. Woodruffe, "who has just taken his degree at Cambridge." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 7, 1837; 7 7/8" x 12 1/2"; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. His work on Washington completed. Intends to push work on Franklin. FILM 54-61 FRAME 220. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 9, 1837; 8" x 10"; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873
    Newport, [R. I.], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to the qualifications of Miss Pierce, a teacher. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 13, 1837; 4 3/8" x 7"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Introducing Count de Castelnau, "who visits the United States for the purpose of scientific researches." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 23, 1837; Blunt, Edmund, 1799-1866
    New York, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p.and add.and end.with reply to Blunt; Aug. 24, 1837. (from original in Haverford College Library, Quaker Collection.) Concerning German made telescope to be used on expedition. Refers to G.W. Blunt. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 24, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Sullivan, William
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Captain Clements, from Quebec. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to the Gentlemen composing the Scientific Corps of the Exploring Expedition, August 24, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    From original in Haverford College Library.
    Regarding telescopes and glasses in Mr. Blunt’s possession. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Aug. 30, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 3, 1837; 8" x 10"; Sedgwick, Catharine Maria, 1789-1867
    Stockbridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Pietro Borsieri. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, September 13, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Has seen the secretary of the navy regarding appointment for Mr. Snider's brother. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Sept. 14, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 20, 1837; 4 15/16" x 7 7/8"; Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Opinion upon sketch to be ordered. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 21, 1837; 12-1/2x8; Hodgson, William Brown, 1800-1871
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.of 2p., one of which bears the endorsement and signature of Condy Raguet. Encloses translation of Arabic manuscript which Raguet desired. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
    Lord's Prayer, written in Arabic, with English-language account of the circumstances of how this writing came to be.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Sept. 23, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 24, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Worcester, J. E.
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards copy of American Almanac for 1838. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1837; 5" x 7 3/4"; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882
    Cambridge, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Lane, a graduate of Harvard, who wishes to become tutor in some gentleman's family. FILM 403 FRAME 139. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 6, 1837; 8 9/16" x 10 3/4"; Robertson, William C.
    Baltimore, 3pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends a stone cannon ball shot at Mary Queen of Scots and Douglass. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Oct. 19, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 24, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Constable, "who visits America for the purpose of inspecting your railroads." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 5, 1837; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 3 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Sends copies of two letters written by George Washington. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Certification in re F.R. Hassler, Nov. 14, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.D.S. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to F.R. Hassler, Nov. 14, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to Dan. Lord, Nov. 14, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Contains also a promissory note for $500 borrowed by F.R. Hassler from John Vaughan; Sept. 19, 1837. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 23, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 3 pp. and address. Copy. Has found "sundry letters of General Washington" among his father's papers. Encloses extracts. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 23, 1837; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 25, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 14, 1837; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Perrine, late American consul at Campeche, who is interested in the introduction of tropical plants into the southern United States. FILM 235 FRAME 4. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 30, 1837; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; Atwater, Caleb
    Circleville, Ohio, 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Political affairs. "We are about to bring forward, as a candidate for the Presidency, a warm friend of Pennsylvania---William Henry Harrison." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Will, 1837-1841; 8" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Codicils dated: Copy of D. 6 leaves " Copy of the will of John Vaughan for the Am. Philos. Society, 1842." Dated May 6, 1837; May 10, 1840; December 7, 1841. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 9, 1838; 8 1/2" x 10 5/8"; Löwenstern, Isidore, 1810-1858 or 9
    New Orleans, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. (In French.) Returns thanks to Vaughan for "the pleasure of your friendly conversation." His travels in the United States and West Indies. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 10, 1838; 8" x 12 1/2"; Hollinshead, Benjamin M.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. and add. Encloses a letter recently received from the Ledyard family [John Ledyard to his mother, Mrs. Abigail Moore; Paris, April 8, 1786, which see] Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 15, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. 3d. per. N.S. Presentation of a chain to Mr. Vaughan upon his eighty-second birthday. Signed by Patterson, J. K. Kane, J. R. Friedlander, Jacob Snider, Jr. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 15, 1838; 7 7/8" x 10"; Taylor, James
    N.W. Penn Square, [Philadelphia], 1 p.and address. A.L.S. Returns thanks "for the volume by Mr. Greenwood." Congratulates Mr. Vaughan upon his birthday. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 3, 1838; Duane, William J. (William John), 1780-1865
    Thanks for engraving by Sartain of W. Y. Birch, based on a drawing by Mr. Sill. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 14, 1838; 7 7/8" x 10 1/8"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    West Chester, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. regrets that he can find no prospect of an appointment for Vaughan's "young friend." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 19, 1838; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Douglass, D. B.
    Brooklyn, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Buckingham, "late of the British Parliament." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, March 5, 1838; 7 13/16" x 9 1/8"; Calderón de la Barca, Ángel
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to the introduction of gas works. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 1, 1838; 8" x 9 3/4"; Bakewell, Benjamin, 1767-1844
    Pittsburgh, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. The Rev. Mr. Bulfinch must leave Pittsburgh, "his health requiring a more congenial climate." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bethune, George W. (George Washington), 1805-1862
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns thanks for book loaned him by Vaughan. Priestley's view of character of Socrates. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 25, 1838; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, L.S. 2p. and add. (see Vaughan club. Papers,1838-1841) Comments on celebration of John Vaughan's 82nd birthday. FILM 54-61 FRAME 221. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 29, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882
    Cambridge, 3 pp., address and endorsement. 2pp. A.L.S.; p. 3 printed prospectus. Returns thanks for DuPonceau's "most valuable work." Concerning J. Bosworth's Dictionary of the Anglo-Saxon Language. FILM403 FRAME 140. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Certification in re Cezard Auguste Millot, June, 1838; 7" x 9 3/4"; Gérard
    Commune de Reynel, A.D.S. 1p. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 3, 1838; 8" x 10"; Buckingham, James Silk, 1786-1855
    [Albany] A.L.S. 1p. and add. On same sheet is printed poem by Buckingham entitled, A contribution for the commemoration of the Fourth of July,1838. Sends him the annexed "Contribution." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 7, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Pickering, John
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Has forwarded twelve copies each of Mr. Young's and Judge White's eulogies. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 16, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. The Franklin Institute is unable to direct Mr. Vaughan to any observations relative to the proportion between evaporation and rain. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, August 18, 1838; 8" x 10"; Schmidt, J.W.
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that his absence prevented him from meeting Mr. [Julius R.] Friedlander. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 1, 1838
    Scope and Contens note
    ALS, Enc. Thanks for “American Historical Anecdote” about Hopkinson’s writing of “Hail Columbia.” Sending the Anecdote and a copy of the poem. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, September 10, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. L.S. Sends two bottles of "vintage" to John Vaughan upon his eighty-second birthday. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 14, 1838; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Worcester, J. E.
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards copy of American Almanac for 1839. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 24, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Custis, C. P.
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards copy of last edition of the Liturgy of King's Chapel, by the Rev. Mr. Greenwood, and a map of Mount Auburn cemetery. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 4, 1838; 8" x 10"; Sigourney, Lydia Huntley
    Hartford, A.L.S. 4p., add. Visit to the rooms of the Philosophical society and the Institution for the blind in Philadelphia; verses about latter visit. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 28, 1838; 5 1/16" x 7 3/4"; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, 1803-1857
    Librarian of A.P.S., Florence, 2 pp. and address. A. L. S. Scheme "to found in Italy a periodical reunion of the Savants." The first to be at Pisa in October of next year. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 3, 1838; 12-3/4x8 6x6-1/2; Hodgson, William Brown, 1800-1871
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p.,end.and enc. of Arabic manuscript written by a Negro slave of Capt. David Anderson's in 1768. enc. of Translates enclosure and comments on it. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, November 7, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Cannot give encouragement for employment of glass-blower. Introducing Dr. [Thomas H.?] Webb of Providence. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 20, 1838; 4 7/8" x 8"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    Philadelphia, 1 p. L.S. Invitation to attend examination of classes of the Pennsylvania Institution for the Instruction of the Blind. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 26, 1838; 4 7/8" x 7 11/16"; Webb, Thomas H. (Thomas Hopkins), 1801-1866
    Congress Hall, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Wishes letter of introduction to the Rev. Mr. Dewey of New York. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, November 28, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gay-Lussac, L.
    Baltimore, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) His travels in the United States. Requests Mr. Vaughan for letters of introduction to any of his friends in Natchez or New Orleans. Incl. ASL J. Vaughan, re. Franklin Chair. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Bill of exchange to John Vaughan, Dec. 1, 1838; 4-1/4x8-1/2; Bank of the United States (Pennsylvania: 1836-1841)
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: N.Biddle and T[homas] Cowperthwait. 1p. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 7, 1838; 8" x 9 7/8"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Mr. Friedlander just visited him, but has now left for St. Augustine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Club song, Jan. 15, 1839; 7 3/4" x 10"; Vaughan Club
    Philadelphia, D.S: William Norris. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 27, [1839?]; 8x5; Combe, George, 1788-1858
    Marshall House, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Regrets missing the Wistar party. Will breakfast with him Tuesday. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 31, 1839; 7 7/8" x 10"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    St. Augustin, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to delay in transmission of his annual report (upon Institution for the Blind). His health, and other personal affairs. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 7, 1839; Duane, William J.(William John),1780-1865.
    Presenting Francis Hoskins' essay, "Navigation made easy, or mariners' complete guide," dated 1803, to the APS. Formerly MISC. MS.
  - Letter to Edward D. Ingraham, Feb. 11, 1839; 8 1/4" x 10 1/4"; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 14, [1839?]; 10x8; Combe, George, 1788-1858
    Marshall House, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asks if he would ask the trustees of his church to rent it for lectures. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 15, 1839; 8" x 9 7/8"; Martineau, Harriet, 1802-1876
    Westminster, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. Mr. Bakewell and his family. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 25, 1839; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Sergeant, John, 1779-1852
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of 22d. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 4, 1839; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Oak Hill, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. James Rumsey and the steamboat. Connection between Rumsey, Lord Stanhope and Robert Fulton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 4, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Thornely, Thomas
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Rev. W. J. Bakewell. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 18, 1839; 8" x 10"; Paulding, James Kirke, 1778-1860 L-5
    Navy Department, [Washington], 1 p. L.S. Acknowledges letter of 5th. inst. enclosing new plan for keeping log book at sea, by Captain F. Beaufort of the British Admiralty. FILM 403 FRAME 30. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 30, 1839; 8" x 10"; Howe, S. G. (Samuel Gridley), 1801-1876
    New Jersey Institution for the Blind, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning the death of Julius R. Friedlander. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 27, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    [London], 2 pp. and address. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of portraits of Bishop White and John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 16, 1839; 7 3/16" x 8 7/8"; Bakewell, W. J.
    Pittsburgh, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Has arrived safely in Pittsburgh. Beauty of scenery along the route. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 6, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    [London], 3 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter announcing the death of his brother, Charles. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 13, 1839; 7 15/16" x 10"; Everett, Alexander Hill, 1790-1847
    Roxbury, Mass., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Ja[me]s A. Roberts. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, June 25, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Calderón de la Barca, Ángel
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledge receipt of letter of May 14. Has been appointed minister to Mexico. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, June 26, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, 2 pp. A.L.S. Encloses note from Mr. Paulding (missing). Hopes to visit Philadelphia by the end of July. Mrs. Sully in Washington. FILM403 FRAME 33. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 9, 1839; 7 15/16" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Mersch of Germany, "a gentleman of literature and science." FILM 235 FRAME 7. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 16, 1839; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    Andalusia, 1 p. Letter of sympathy upon Mr. Vaughan's accident. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 17, 1839; 7 7/8" x 10"; Alexander, J. H.
    Lonaconing, Md., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Letter of sympathy upon "Personal misfortune" which Vaughan recently met. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 18, 1839; 8" x 10"; Short, C. W.
    Louisville, Ky., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Samuel Kennedy, of Louisville. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 19, 1839; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Bachman, John, 1790-1874
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Letter of sympathy upon Vaughan's accident; congratulations upon the prospect of his prompt recovery. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 2, 1839; 8x9-1/2; Priestley, Joseph Rayner
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Is glad to hear of Mr. Vaughan's recovery from his accident. Has Mr. Snider's receipts for accounts for 1838 and 1839. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 16, 1839; 7 7/8" x 10"; Dunbar, William, MD, 1793-1847
    Forest, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. M. E. Pierpont, Of New Haven, Connecticut. Hopes that Mr. Vaughan has recovered from his accident. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 17, 1839; 7 3/4" x 10"; Abbott, Harriet Vaughan
    Farmington, Maine, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing the bearer, Mr. Charles Perkins. Is rejoiced by Mr. Vaughan's "providential" recovery from injury. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 21, 1839; 5" x 8"; Worcester, J. E.
    Cambridge, 1 p. A.L.S. Forwards copy of American Almanac for 1840. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Webb, Thomas H. (Thomas Hopkins), 1801-1866
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Louis DeFernex, of Geneva, Switzerland. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 5, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 3 pp. and address. L.Initialled. Account of his birthday celebration on September 23. Advises John to take better care of himself since his accident. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, October 11, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning invention of process for reproduction of facsimiles of printing and writing, by [Joseph] Dixon of Taunton. Newspaper clipping enclosed. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 30, 1839; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing his son, who will "spend the winter in Philadelphia as a student of chemistry with Dr. Hare." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 20, 1839; 5" x 8"; Sill, Joseph
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. Announcing the birth of his child, named Vaughan Sill. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 22, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Concerning set of Birds of America for the king of Sardinia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 16, 1839; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Ellis, George E.
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Alexander Barclay. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 16, 1839; 7 3/4" x 10"; Short, C. W.
    Louisville, Ky., 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of book notices. Collecting material for work upon the botany of central North America. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 21, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bigelow, Jacob, 1786-1879
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Inquiring as to the whereabouts of Mr. Ball Hughes, sculptor, who received $240 toward a bust of Nathaniel Bowditch and then disappeared. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 11, 1840; 8 3/8" x 10 1/2"; Dunlap, Thomas
    Bank of the United States, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Accepts invitation to Vaughan's 84th. birthday anniversary. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 15, 1840; Sergeant, John, 1779-1852
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. end address. A.L.S. Asks Mr. Vaughan to use his influence to assist George G. Meade to secure a position in Mr. Hassler's corps. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Daniel J. Desmond, January 16, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841